这是个真实的故事...
英国  泽西岛  1879
你们是谁
Who are you?
你们在做什么
What are you doing?
我们将把这建成高尔夫球场
There's a golf Iinks going in here.
高尔夫球是什么东西
What's golf?
高尔夫球是绅士们玩的比赛
Golf is a game played by gentlemen.
不是你这样的人玩的
Not for the Iikes of you.
快走开  孩子
Now, run along, boy.
布鲁克莱恩  马萨诸塞州  1900
在这儿  先生
Here it is, sir.
快点  我们走
Come on! Let's go!
就是这样  坐直  莎拉
That's it. Sit up straight, Sarah.
轻轻拉缰绳
Lightly on the reins. There.
这就是我们要做的  弗朗西斯
This is how we do it, Francis.
我们努力工作  把钱拿回家
We work hard, and we bring home the money.
努力工作  把钱拿回家
Work hard. Bring home the money.
-吉尔勒莫  -是
- Guillermo! - Yes, sir!
快点
Come on!
弗朗西斯  你究竟在做什么
Francis, what in the world are you doin'?
已经后半夜了
It's after midnight!
你会吵醒你弟弟的  上床去
You're keepin' your brother up. Go to bed.
雷德蒙  上床睡觉  不许说话
Raymond, go to sleep. No talkin'.
我的意思是  不要发出声音
No noises. I mean it.
你在干吗  弗朗西斯
What have you got there, Francis? Hmm?
弗朗西斯
Francis.
我能去看他吗  爸爸
Can I see him, Father? PIease?
他在说什么  看谁
What's he talking about? See who?
哈利·瓦顿
Harry Vardon.
打这种比赛的绅士
Any gentleman who plays this game
没有一个是你的朋友
is not a friend to you.
我知道
I know.
但他是目前最出色的
But he's the greatest ever.
-亚瑟  我想这没有什么坏处  -不要说了
- Arthur, I don't see the harm in... - Not another word.
他今天得去学校
The boy goes to school today.
就谈到这儿
That's the end of it.
达西小姐  帮我照顾下小孩
Mrs. Darcy, mind the Iittle one!
他会去爬楼梯的
He'II try to climb those stairs.
弗朗西斯  放下书
Francis, Ieave your books.
我要去买东西  你跟我一起去
I've got shoppin' to do. You come with me now.
爸爸说我得去学校
Father said I had to go to school.
你一天不去学校没有关系
You can miss school for one day.
而且我需要人帮提包  走吧
Besides, I need help with me packages. Come along.
是什么事情引起这么大的骚动
What could be causing such a fuss?
去吧  我会去找你
Go on. I'II find ya.
谢谢  女士们  先生们
Thank you, Iadies and gentlemen.
我希望你们能帮忙
I'II now presume upon your goodwill
我需要个志愿者
and request the services of a volunteer.
谁愿意上来
Anyone?
你好  你叫什么名字
Hello. What's your name?
-弗朗西斯  -你好  弗朗西斯先生
- Francis. - Hello, Mr. Francis.
你知道这是什么吗
Now, do you know what this is?
高尔夫球杆
A brassie.
是的  打一杆吧
So it is. Have a bash.
继续
Go on.
不错  弗朗西斯  即使在最灰暗的日子
That's all right, Francis. Even in our darkest hour,
我们也得时刻记住  我们永不绝望
we must always remember, you never despair.
你有没有把一只小鸟握在手上过
Have you held a Iive bird in your hands?
握的时候不能太用力  否则会伤到它
Not too hard to hurt her.
只要不让它飞走就可以了
Just firm enough to stop it from flying away.
再试试
Try it again.
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
欢迎常胜将军
Hail the conquering hero!
达尔文先生
Mr. Darwin.
-是不是如同我所想的一样  -我不确定  哈利
- Is this what I think it is? - I'm not sure, Harry.
我跟你一样
I received a summons from Lord Northcliffe,
-得到了诺斯克利夫爵士的召唤  -不用找了
- just as you did. - Keep the change, mate.
-他正在里面等着  -今天是特别的一天
- He's waiting inside. - Today's the day.
但是  哈利  从没有一个非职业选手
But, Harry, no professional has ever been asked
加入过绅士们的高尔夫俱乐部
to join a gentlemen's golf club as a member.
任何事都会有个开始  伯纳德
First time for everything, Bernard.
-是的  -瞧瞧这个地方
- Yes. - Look at this place.
他们为什么会让你过来
Why else would they want you here?
他不信任我  我只是为他工作
He doesn't confide in me. I only work for him.
十年前  我还是个修剪篱笆的
Ten years ago, I was clippin' hedges.
不可思议
Marvelous.
干得太漂亮了  哈利
Brilliantly done, Harry.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
如果你们这些绅士愿意  把它加入到你们的战利品
I'd be honored if you gentlemen would consider
-我将感到很荣幸  -一个闪闪发光的奖杯
- adding it to your trophy case. - A glittering addition.
我们很高兴为你保留这个  是吧  奈维尔
We'd be pleased to keep it for you. Wouldn't we, Neville?
你很大方
Handsome.
不过你要想再拿回去  恐怕就不是那么容易了
But you might not get it back without a tussle.
我也没想过能轻松的把它拿回来
Don't plan on handing it back myself without a fight.
哈利  进入正题吧
Harry, I'II come to the point.
我们俱乐部有个公开赛
We've had an opening at our club.
这位是布洛克爵士  俱乐部委员会主席
Lord Bullock chairs the membership committee.
你父亲是做什么的
What does your father do?
先生  他是泽西岛上的一个园丁
Uh, he's a gardener on Jersey, sir.
我听说你是信奉罗马天主教的
I'm told you're Church of Rome.
-你母亲是法国人吗  -是的
- Mother's French? - Yes, sir.
我想我们可以暂时不管这个
I believe we can work around it.
就这么决定了  你是我们想找的人
It's decided, then. You're just the man for us.
嗯  我都不知道说什么了  先生
Well, I don't know what to say, sir.
好了  就说好吧
Well, say yes.
我们希望你替我们工作  有相当好的收入
We want you to work for us. Decent wage.
你可以经营自己的店
You can run your own shop.
当然还可以开班上课  收取你想要的费用
Lessons, of course. Charge what you Iike for those.
你是唯一一个能帮我解决问题的人
You're the only man who can set me right.
你得停止你的工作
You'II have your work cut out.
我想到处都是酒
I think it's drinks all around.
我说过  你替我们工作
I'm told you'll work for us...
高尔夫球是绅士们打的比赛
Golf is a game played by gentlemen.
不是你这样的人玩的  绅士们打的比赛
Not for the likes of you. Played by gentlemen.
可以经营你自己的商店  有相当好的收入
Run your own shop. Decent wage.
快走开  小孩
Run along, boy.
弗朗西斯  已经下半夜了
Francis. It's after midnight.
妈妈  最后一个球
Just one more, Mother.
黑斯廷斯先生
Mr. Hastings!
-啊  弗朗西斯大师  -先生
- Ah, Master Francis. - Sir.
我们现在需要一个实战
We now Iack but one essential
来完成我们的既定目标
to complete the swift appointment of our round:
-你的俱乐部赛  -我的俱乐部赛吗  先生
- Your clubs. - My clubs, sir?
球童是不能打全程的  如果坎贝尔先生发现我在
Caddies aren't allowed on the course. If Mr. Campbell sees me out there...
我来帮你考虑坎贝尔的事  你快去  挥动那些球棒
You Iet me worry about Campbell. Go. Get those clubs.
快去  孩子  挥动那些球棒
You go, boy. Get those clubs.
-挥杆不错  伙计  -谢谢  先生
- Well struck, Iad. - Thank you, sir.
你用了多少杆
What did you shoot?
81杆  先生
Uh, an 81, sir.
第15洞你用了多少杆
What did you take on 1 5?
9杆  先生
A nine, sir.
第一次在新英格兰最难的场地
So you shot an 81 first time around
打完全程用了81杆
on the toughest golf course in New England?
-其中有个洞还用了9杆  -嗯  我  我想我
- With a nine? - Well, I... I think I...
我看到你站在那儿  知道球童是不允许打
I saw you standing there, knowing caddies aren't supposed to play...
继续说
Go on.
我  我想我有些紧张  先生
I... I think I got a Iittle nervous, sir.
我们得看看你是如何控制自己的
We needed to see how you handled yourself.
控制我自己
Handled myself?
下个月有全国业余锦标赛
National Amateur Championship's here next month.
你是说  我可以
Are you saying that I can...
我该做什么
What do I have to do?
-你得去跟那些有资格的人比赛  -很容易的
- You have to play in the qualifier. - That's the easy part.
你要让竞赛委员同意你参赛
You have to be approved by the executive committee.
你是这儿的球童吗
You're a caddie here?
是的  做了10年
Yes, sir. For ten years.
为了成为业余选手  最近已经不作了
I recently resigned to preserve my status as an amateur.
什么  没有计划做职业选手吗
What, no plans to turn professional?
没有  我准备从商
Uh, no, sir. I plan to have a career in business.
-哦  做生意  -是的
- Oh, business? - Yes.
什么样的生意
What sort of business?
霍华德  我们得
Howard, we need...
对不起  你们继续吧
Sorry. Carry on.
你的主俱乐部在哪儿  这上面没写
What's your home club? I don't see it here.
他们得赞助你
They have to sponsor you.
我的主俱乐部
My home club?
-我正在多个俱乐部之间选择  -哦  听好了
- I'm between clubs at the moment. - Look, see here.
你可能有资格做一个选手
you may have qualified as a player,
但这不是球童做的事情
but this just isn't the sort of thing that caddies do.
你是个球童
You're a caddie?
是的  先生  我曾经是
Yes, sir, I was.
球童不能进行业余选手比赛  你不能参加这比赛
Caddies don't play in the Amateur. It's not for your kind.
只有会员才可以参加
Members only.
我们场地委员会要讨论公开赛的问题了
We need to discuss the opening on the greens committee.
对不起  但是  总可以让那些
I'm sorry. But there must be a way
非会员的人也来参加比赛吧
for somebody who's not a member to compete.
今年不行
Not this year.
如果他能支付50美元的入场费
As if he could afford the $50 entrance fee.
对不起  先生
Excuse me. Sir...
如果我能支付50美元的话
...if I were to pay the $50,
是不是我就可以加入俱乐部了
would I need to belong to a club?
理论上不可以
Technically, no.
你仍然需要一个有名望的俱乐部成员  来担保  而且
You would still need a club member in good standing to sponsor you, and...
而且  由我来担保
And... that would be me.
打高尔夫球要50美元
Fifty dollars to play golf.
我会把挣的钱全部拿回家的
I'II pay back every penny from my earnings.
我对你很失望  弗朗西斯  这就是你从我这儿学到的吗
Is this how I failed you? Is that all you've Iearned from me?
不是的  先生  但这只是场比赛
No, sir. But it's just a game.
比赛
A game?
比赛不能让一个男人过活  不能让他养家
A game doesn't give a man what he needs to make a Iife, feed his family.
你说的对  但是如果我赢了  就会有伟大的事情发生
If I win, great things could happen.
什么也不会发生
Nothing will happen.
他们会按他们的喜好来利用你
They'II use you for their own amusement.
我能成功的  这是我所擅长的
I can do this. This is something I'm good at.
如果是你  你会怎么做
What if you do?
你怎么来获得那50美元
What will you get for your $50?
我也有过梦想  弗朗西斯
I had dreams too, Francis.
无论你做什么
No matter what you do,
他们都不会让你通过那条街的
they'II never Iet you cross that street.
我想要的就是个机会
AII I want is a chance.
好的
OK.
我们打个赌吧
OK, we make a bargain.
你发誓  如果你输了  就不再打高尔夫球
You promise me if you Iose, no more golf.
你得放弃那愚蠢的比赛
You give up this fool's game.
去完成你的学业  你得学贸易
You finish your schooling, you Iearn a trade,
把你靠诚实劳动获得的钱拿回家
and you bring home an honest wage.
是说我不合格吗
If I don't qualify?
好的  我答应你
Yes, I promise.
这是英文版的  这儿都没有出版
It's the English edition. It's not even in print here yet.
哈利·瓦顿
Harry Vardon.
谢谢
Thank you.
好好学习吧
Read it, study it.
你必须打到78杆  才有资格
You'II need a 78 to qualify.
艰苦的竞赛
Stiffer competition.
他们是这个国家最好的业余选手
These are the best amateurs in the country.
你认为我能行吗
Do you think I'm ready?
我不知道  只有你参加了后  你才能知道
I don't know, and neither will you until you're in it.
只是高尔夫球比赛  是冠军杯
There's golf, and there's championship golf.
帮我保管一下  我要去参加舞会
Keep it for me. I'm going to the party.
他们说邀请所有的选手参加
They said all the players are invited.
舞会是什么样的
What's it Iike in there?
我也不知道  我不能进去
I couldn't tell you. I'm not allowed inside.
能帮我一下吗
Do me a favor, would you?
嘿  这个男孩我以前见过  在去学校的时候他在后面追我
Hi. This boy I used to see before I Ieft for college is after me.
-假装你要请我跳舞  -你在这啊  小甜心
- Pretend you asked me to dance. - There you are, you peach.
你不能整晚都躲我
You know, you can't avoid me all evening.
我说过要跳一支舞  菲利普
I... I said a dance, Phillip.
但不是这支
Not this one.
-我答应这位  -弗朗西斯·奥密特
- I promised this one to... - Francis Ouimet.
-我知道你家族吗  -不清楚
- Do I know your family? - I don't know.
-菲利普·韦恩赖特  -韦恩赖特
- Phillip Wainwright? - Wainwright?
啊  是的  韦恩赖特家族  很好的人
Oh, yes. Wainwrights, good people.
韦恩赖特家族
Wainwrights.
好了  时间还早  她会和你跳舞的
Well, the evening's young. She'II catch up with you.
你真是个好伙伴  帮了我大忙
You're a real sport for helping.
又没有什么麻烦
It's no trouble.
我今天疯了
I had the craziest day.
我从费城坐火车来  我把包丢在巴尔的摩了
I take a train from Philadelphia, my bags end up in Baltimore.
我的晚礼服也给落在巴尔的摩了
My tux is in the bags in Baltimore.
我现在穿的是男仆的衣服
I'm wearing the houseman's suit.
不过你看起来不错
I think you Iook just fine.
你也是
You too.
他走了吗
Is he gone?
没有  他还在看着
No, he's still watching.
我们跳支舞  好吗
Shall we dance?
你刚才说你要去上大学  是吗
You said you were going to college?
史密斯学院  第一个学期
Smith. First semester.
哦
Oh.
你呢
Where are you going?
读哪所大学
To college?
我要花一年时间考虑一下我的选择
I'm taking the year off to consider my options.
我想这是明智之举
I think that's so wise.
可能你会去欧洲
Perhaps you'II go to Europe.
可能吧  因为我的家在法国
Perhaps I will. 'Cause I have family in France.
对不起  你能不能再说一次你的名字
I'm sorry. What did you say your name was again?
弗朗西斯·奥密特
Francis. Ouimet.
哦  瞧  那是我哥哥
Oh, Iook! There's my brother!
-弗雷迪  来认识一下弗朗西斯  -弗雷迪
- Freddie, you must know Francis. - Freddie.
球童
Caddie Boy.
弗雷迪  你真会开玩笑
Freddie, you're such a kidder.
爸妈  这是弗朗西斯·奥密特
Dad, Mother, this is Francis Ouimet.
你好
How do you do?
衣服很漂亮
That's a beautiful dress.
弗朗西斯是个比赛选手
Francis is playing in the tournament.
是的  我知道
Yes, yes, I know.
你们男人谈吧  我和妈妈一会过来
Well, you boys chat. Mother and I will be right back.
你女儿很漂亮
Swell girl, your daughter.
年轻人  你可以被邀请过来
Young man, you may have been invited,
但是你别指望你能属于这
but don't get the idea that you belong here.
有两类选手
There are only two types of player:
一类是绷着神经要赢比赛
Those who keep their nerves in control and win championships,
另一类却相反
and those who do not.
最多只能用5杆  你就能进入下一轮了
Five or Iess, and you make the cut.
第18洞  我闭着眼睛都只用5杆
Eighteen? I can make five here in my sleep.
搞定
That's the one.
祝贺你
Congratulations.
太糟糕了  球童
That's too bad, Caddie Boy.
你可以在比赛中当我的球童
You could caddie for me in the tournament.
你还是有用的  不是吗
You're available, right?
祝贺你  儿子  打得不错
Congratulations, son. Well played.
要组建帝国  哈利
Empire, Harry.
否则阳光永远不会照到我们  一群废物
The sun never sets on us, all that rubbish.
说到荣耀  希腊的亚历山大是最伟大的
Consider the glory that was Greece of AIexander the Great.
现在你在地图上都找不到
Now you can't even find it on a map.
希腊将体育运动传播给世界
Greece introduced sport to the world,
纯粹地表达他们的优越感
pure expression of their superiority.
我们应该走他们的路
We've trodden that same road.
足球  板球  橄榄球  高尔夫球
Football, cricket, rugby, golf.
让英国能举办所有重要的锦标赛
AII the major championships remain in British hands.
得一分
Save one.
你有什么打算
What are you proposing?
美国公开赛
The U.S. Open.
你以前赢过的
You won it before.
我要你对美国人展开
I want you to mount a new campaign
一场新的战役
to do to the Americans
就像亚历山大对波斯人做的那样
what AIexander did to the Persians.
让他们都变成废物
Lay waste to 'em.
我的书会占领所有市场
My papers get exclusive coverage.
伯纳德会在一旁把你的胜利记录在册
Bernard here comes along to chronicle your conquest.
这是我们的比赛
It's our game, man.
从他们的公开赛上  把奖杯拿回来
Win their Open and bring back that trophy.
当然  奖金归你
You pocket your winnings, of course.
-不用出路费吗  先生  -所有的费用都不用
- Wouldn't pay for the crossing, sir. - AII expenses paid.
正好搞个展览巡游  主办方安排一切
As part of an exhibition tour, all sponsors arranged.
有兴趣吗
Does that cover it?
好的  那就做吧
Yep. That'd do it.
我还听到一些关于
And I hear there's talk
俱乐部成员荣誉的谈论
of an honorary membership at the club.
也能够一起解决
This would clinch it.
我料想国王会对英格兰  最伟大的运动员
And I daresay His Majesty might want to show his gratitude
表示谢意的
to England's greatest sportsman.
哈利·瓦顿  大英帝国
Harry Vardon, Order of the British Empire.
会给你带上一枚漂亮的戒指
Has a nice ring to it.
我需要一个合作伙伴  能和我分享的伙伴
I'II need a partner. Somebody to share the workload with.
这正是我所想的
My thoughts exactly.
威尔弗雷德跟你去  他是大不列颠业余比赛冠军
Wilfred here is your man. Top amateur in the British Isles.
太荣幸了
Delighted, old chap.
高兴得合不拢嘴了  是吧
Jolly good wheeze, what?
给那些美国佬一个沉重的打击
Giving the Yanks a thorough thrashing.
我有人选了
I had someone else in mind.
特德·雷
Ted Ray?
天哪  他是西哥特人
Christ, he's a Visigoth.
不  他是泽西人
No, he's a Jerseyman.
借过
'Scuse me.
下注结束
AII bets off!
-快点  -快点
- Come on! - Come on!
-特德  -哈利
- Ted! - Harry!
嘿  瞧瞧
Hey! Look at you!
这就是你手下的大师
What's this, another night out with your ruling class masters?
这是特德·雷  这位是诺斯克利夫爵士
Ted Ray, Lord Northcliffe.
诺斯克利夫爵士  非常荣幸
Lord Northcliffe? The honor is entirely mine.
你怎么过来了  哈利
What brings you down this way, Harry?
你好  你好
Hello, hello
停止你的游戏吧
Stop your little games
不要以为这就是适合你的路
Don't you think your ways you ought to mend
你相信吗  他们把公开赛推迟了三个月
Can you believe they moved the Open back three months
就是为了让一个家伙参赛
just so one guy can play in it?
啊  他可是哈利·瓦顿
Well, he's Harry Vardon,
设计师  灰狗[哈利·瓦顿的绰号]
The Stylist, The Greyhound.
如果他住在月球上  我就不关心
I don't care if he's the man in the moon.
他们不可能为一个美国人这么做的
They wouldn't do that for an American.
问问弗朗西斯  他以前参加过
Ask Francis. He used to play.
-你参加过  -不  没有
- You did? - No, not really.
哈  他这是谦虚
Ah, he's being modest.
他过去很优秀的  不过他放弃了
He used to be good before he gave it up
为了做生意  是这样的吗  弗朗西斯
for the glamour of retail. Isn't that right, Francis?
弗朗西斯
Francis!
凯西要与金发碧眼的姑娘跳华尔兹
Casey would waltz with the strawberry blonde
乐队一直在演奏
And the band played on
他与心爱的姑娘在地上轻轻的移动
He'd glide 'cross the floor with the girl he adored
乐队一直在演奏
And the band played on
他的脑袋紧张欲裂
His brain was so loaded it nearly exploded
可怜的姑娘被惊慌摇晃
The poor girl would shake with alarm
他永远不会离开
He 'd ne 'er leave the girl
这个有草莓卷一样秀发的姑娘
With the strawberry curl
乐队一直在演奏
And the band played on
意大利语演唱
哦  太动听了
Oh, well. It was glorious.
-是不是很动听  -是的
- Wasn't it glorious? - Yes, it was.
你以前听过这样的声音吗
Have you ever heard such a voice?
就像  音乐就像从某个地方发出来
It was Iike the... the music was coming through her
穿透她的身体一样
from someplace else.
这就是我的感受  我常常想
That's the feeling I've always wanted...
弗朗西斯  想什么
Francis, for what? Hmm?
他在那儿  弗朗西斯  过来一下
There he is. Francis! Come here.
过来见一下罗伯特·沃森
Meet Robert Watson,
美国高尔夫球协会会长
president of the United States Golf Association.
弗朗西斯  很高兴见到你
Francis, pleasure.
很高兴见到您
Well, the pleasure's mine, sir.
嗯  我找个售货员  来给你介绍一下我们的产品
Uh, Iet me have a salesman show you our equipment.
-这是波士顿最好的商店  -他不是来买球棍的
- It's the best selection in Boston. - He's not here to buy clubs.
我听说你住在布鲁克林  离国家俱乐部不远
I hear you Iive in Brookline, not far from the country club.
就在街对面
Right across the street.
我们将在那儿举行公开赛  为期2个星期
We're holding our Open Championship there in two weeks.
-你被提名了  -提名  先生
- Your name came up. - My name, sir?
我们准备让当地的一名业余选手参加
I'm Iooking to add a Iocal amateur to the field.
哈利·瓦顿也来参赛了  还有特德·雷
Harry Vardon's playing. And Ted Ray.
沃森先生  很感谢  但是我不能接受
Mr. Watson, thank you, but I can't accept.
-为什么不  -这儿的工作很忙
- Why not? - I'm awfully busy here.
嗯  我不再打高尔夫了
And, uh, I don't play golf anymore.
-你多大了  弗朗西斯  -20了  先生
- How old are you, Francis? - I'm 20, sir.
这个年龄放弃梦想  太年轻了  不是吗
Awfully young to be giving up on your dreams, aren't you?
我只是有特殊的原因  就是这样
I just have different ones now, that's all.
对不起  黑斯廷斯先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Hastings.
没有必要解释  弗朗西斯
There's no need to explain, Francis.
祝你好运
AII the best.
这个挥杆好熟悉啊
That swing Iooks familiar.
你来这儿做什么
What are you doing here?
我父亲带我出来走走
Father's taking me out for our annual round.
我哥哥说你在这儿工作
My brother said that you were working here.
你哥哥  我在这儿见过他几次
Your brother. I've seen him in here a couple times.
我希望你能卖给我些装备
I was hoping you could sell me some equipment.
我实际上不是个销售人员
I'm not actually the salesman.
还在思考你的选择吗
Still considering your options?
是的
Yeah.
我去帮你找个销售员来
I'II go get you a salesman.
好的
AII right.
哈利·瓦顿
Harry Vardon.
设计师[哈利·瓦顿的绰号]正在进行练习赛
The Stylist. Practice round.
我们期待有大量的观众  所以邀请名人很重要
We're expecting a big turnout, so it's important we have marshals here...
沃森先生  弗朗西斯·奥密特
Mr. Watson. Francis Ouimet.
-我能和你谈一下吗  先生  -什么事
- Can I speak to you, sir? - What is it?
如果出价合适的话  我愿意为你参加比赛
If that offer is still good, I'd Iove to take you up on it.
现在很忙  我们得考虑一下
We have to think about that.
-我不要钱  -你能给我们些时间吗  弗朗西斯
- I'm not asking for favors... - Can you give us a moment?
格罗夫大街怎么样
What about Grove Street?
明天一大早来这儿见我
Meet me here, sunup.
你有些工作要做
You've got some work to do.
1913  美国公开赛资格赛
比利  我们在哪儿
Billy, where do we stand?
抽到76号签
Cut Iine's 76.
用4杆完成6号洞
Six holes to make up four shots.
怎么啦  有什么问题吗
What is it? What's wrong?
-你刚才在6号洞打出了小鸟球  -真的吗
- You just made six straight birdies. - I did?
祝贺你  小伙子  你进入公开赛了
Congratulations, Iad. You're in the Open.
先生们
Gentlemen?
不管是职业选手  还是业余选手
I want to welcome you all, professionals and amateurs alike,
欢迎来参加第八届美国公开赛
to the 1 8th United States Open Championship.
在接下来的两天  有4轮高尔夫球赛
Four rounds of golf to be played over the next two days
通过比赛选出世界上最好的选手
to identify the best player in the world.
让我们欢迎
Let's give a special welcome
大不列颠业余比赛冠军  威尔弗雷德·里德
to the British Amateur Champion, Mr. Wilfred Reid...
还有著名的职业选手
...and our famous professional visitors,
哈利·瓦顿和特德·雷
Harry Vardon and Ted Ray.
我们防守方的冠军
I'II yield the floor to our defending champion,
欢迎来自费城的职业选手约翰·麦克德莫特
a professional from Philadelphia, John McDermott.
如果你看报纸的话  上面有很多消息
If you read the papers, there's a Iot of talk
关于伟大英国冠军远渡来到这  参加我们的公开赛的消息
about the great English champions sailing over here to play in our Open.
关于只有美国人能赢得这个奖杯的消息
As the only born American to win this cup,
我想说  欢迎你们
I'd Iike to say to you boys, welcome.
-我们对你们的到来感到很高兴  -听听
- We're happy to have you. - Hear, hear.
我们都知道哈利·瓦顿赢过这个比赛
We know Harry Vardon was winning Opens
那是很久以前了  当我们还在呀呀学语时
back when most of us were Iearning our ABC's.
在这项运动的历史上  他是个天才
He's a genius in the history of our game.
瓦顿先生  我知道  你在这项赛事成立的早期赢得过比赛
Mr. Vardon, I know you won this baby once before.
我在这里看到过你的名字
I see your name here.
但是看起来那是很久以前的事了
It's a Iong time ago, by the Iook of it.
我们希望你们能在波士顿过得愉快
Well, we hope you boys have a nice time here in Boston.
我个人认为  那不可能
Personally, I don't think you will.
我不关心在以后的六个星期  你们是否会大胜我们
I don't care if you whupped us the Iast six weeks.
我讨厌人们谈的都是你能赢比赛的消息
I'm tired of people saying all you have to do to win is show up!
这次  你他妈的  不可能把这个杯给捧回去了
This time you're not taking our damn cup back!
真想把那家伙给干掉
Might just have to kill that one.
-祝你好运  先生  -谢谢你  先生
- Good Iuck, sir. - Thank you, sir.
比利
Billy.
明天早上见面如何
See you first thing tomorrow morning?
-不行  -为什么
- I can't. - Well, why not?
这个英国人出了20美元  如果他赢了的话
This English fella offered me 20 bucks,
会给我50美元
50 if he wins.
我无法支付那样的价格
Well, I can't give you anything Iike that.
对不起  弗朗西斯  我得回家照顾两个孩子
I'm sorry, Francis. I've got two kids at home.
坎贝尔先生  我的球童走了
Mr. Campbell? I just Iost my caddie.
你认识别的球童吗
Do you know somebody?
-对不起  所有的都被雇完了  -那我该怎么办
- Sorry, all the Iads are taken. - What am I supposed to do?
自己解决问题  你认为瓦顿和雷
Hitch up your knickers. You think Vardon and Ray
会因为你自己背装备而同情你吗
will take pity because you carry your own bag?
这是公开赛  每个人只为自己
This is the Open. Every man for himself.
我该怎么办
What am I doing here?
嘿  弗朗西斯
Hey, Francis!
杰克  你来这儿做什么
Jack! What are you doin' here?
我和埃迪翘课  过来看看练习赛
Me and Eddie hooked school to come watch the practice round.
你还在富兰克林公园做球童吗
Are you still caddying out at Franklin Park?
-是的  -你能不能
- That's right. - Any chance you can
明天帮我当球童
carry for me tomorrow?
-在公开赛上吗  -是的
- In the Open? - Yeah.
你原来的那个球童怎么啦
Well, what happened to your guy?
他找到了个更好的雇主
He got a better offer.
说明那个家伙是个大肥猪  对吗
Then that guy's a big, fat jerk! What?
杰克  如果你愿意的话
Jack, if you're gonna do this,
明天早上7:30之前到这儿来
you gotta be here tomorrow at 7':30 sharp.
快答应
Do it!
埃迪能来吗
Can Eddie come too?
杰克  我不能改变规则
Jack, I can't change the rules.
只允许你一个人背包
You're only allowed one man on the bag.
也许他能和我们一起  帮记记分数
Maybe he could walk with us and keep score.
我们会解决的
We'II figure it out.
-可以吗  -好的
- Is that OK with you? - Sure.
弗朗西斯  成交
Francis, you got yourself a deal.
太好了  杰克  太好了
That's great, Jack. That's great.
再见  埃迪
I'II see ya, Eddie.
我来开门  亨利
I'II get it, Henry!
你来做什么
And what do you want?
我想和莎拉说句话  她在吗
I was hopin' to speak to Sarah. Is she here?
她去上学了
She Ieft for college.
-什么时候  今天吗  -是的
- When, today? - Yeah.
帮我给她带个口信
Give her a message for me.
是谁  弗雷迪
Who was that, Freddie?
是  没什么人  只是个小贩
Ah, it was... it was no one. It was a peddler.
你听说过球童参加公开赛的事情吗
Did you hear about the caddie playing in the Open?
这种事从未发生过  各方面都异常关心
It should never have happened. Reflects badly on all concerned.
照我说  没有什么比
I say, if he wants to go out and play
让他比赛丢丑更好的了
and make a fool of himself again, so much the better.
-你们在谈论谁  -是俱乐部的事情
- Who are you talking about? - It's a club matter.
球童
Caddie Boy.
奥密特
Ouimet.
还坚持说他是个业余选手  这个世界怎么啦
Insists he's an amateur. What is the world coming to?
-再要些汤吗  先生  -好的  哈利
- More bisque, sir? - Thank you, Henry.
奥德丽今晚为我们准备了什么派
And what kind of pie does Audrey have for us tonight?
-越橘派  先生  -太好了
- Huckleberry, sir. - Ah. Splendid.
你以为能一直瞒着我
Did you think you could keep it from me?
我从未试过
I didn't try to.
你的名字出现在报纸上了  总是背着我做
Your name is in the newspaper, sneaking around behind my back.
不是的  爸爸
No, no, no, Father...
你必须停下来
You're going to stop this now.
一个男人应该知道自己的位置  并且静下心去做
A man knows his place and makes his peace with it.
-我不想谈这个  -那你就听着吧
- I can't talk about this. - Then you Iisten.
这是为你好
This is for your own good.
我试图保护你
I am trying to protect you.
保护我什么
Protect me from what?
弗朗西斯  那些人  不需要在世上找自己的位子
Francis, those men don't have to earn a place in this world.
这是他们的世界
It's given to them.
不是我们这些人的
We're not those kind of people.
你现在去告诉他们  你不参赛了
Now, you go tell them that you can't do this.
就说这只是个错误
It's a mistake.
我不会这么做的
I won't do that.
你答应过我的
You gave me your word.
我现在不能放弃  对不起
I can't quit now. I'm sorry.
那就帮我个忙  当这一切结束后
Then so help me, when this is over,
你自己找个其他的地方住吧
you find somewhere else to Iive.
好的
Fine.
你确信这些人都受过礼仪教育
Make sure these people get the etiquette guide.
他们大多数人  以前都没有参加高尔夫课程
Most of them have never been on a golf course before.
天哪
God help us.
奥密特先生
Mr. Ouimet!
埃迪
Eddie!
杰克在哪儿  我等了他10分钟了
Where's Jack? I tee off in ten minutes.
他被逮着了  现在在学校
Truant officer caught him. He's in school.
-为什么你没有和他在一起  -天哪  这可是美国公开赛
- Why aren't you with him? - Come on! This is the U.S. Open.
谢谢你过来告诉我
Thanks for coming to tell me.
奥密特先生  我可以为你当球童
Mr. Ouimet, I can caddie for you.
埃迪  我的包和你一样高
Eddie, my bag is as big as you are.
但是我可以做到
But I can do it!
在富兰克林公园  我帮很多人背过包  你去问问
I carry for Iots of fellas at Franklin Park. Ask 'em.
我能做得和杰克一样好
I came to make good on what Jack promised.
我从学校逃课  坐了3辆电车  我够高了
I hooked school, took three streetcars and I am big enough!
我5年级了  我想为你当球童
I'm in 5th grade, and I want to caddie for you!
先安静一下
Calm down for a second.
这样如何  我背包  你跟着我
How about this? I'II carry my bag, and you walk next to me.
-不行  奥密特先生  -叫我弗朗西斯
- No, Mr. Ouimet! - Call me Francis.
-我能办到  奥密特先生  -叫我弗朗西斯
- I can do it, Mr. Ouimet. - Francis.
我知道你的名字  我看过你的比赛
I know your game. I've seen you play.
-我可以背那个包  -好吧  好吧
- I can carry that bag! - AII right. AII right.
你可以当我的球童  好吗  但是你必须叫我弗朗西斯
You can caddie for me. OK? But you're gonna have to call me Francis.
-好的  弗朗西斯  -好吧
- OK, Francis. - AII right.
你们有毛病吗
You got a problem?
现在是9:45  开球时间
This is the 9:45 tee time.
卡托沃基高尔夫俱乐部的
The professional from Cattawaukee Golf CIub,
阿尔伯特·莫里
AIbert Murray.
来自马萨诸塞州布鲁克莱恩的
From Brookline, Massachusetts,
业余选手弗朗西斯·奥密特
amateur Mr. Francis Ouimet.
不管你决定做什么  弗朗西斯
Whatever you decide, Francis,
冷静下来  我会看着球的
keep your head down and I'II watch the ball.
我们肯定能打进那个洞
We're gonna par this hole.
就该这样  打好每一球
That's the stuff. One shot at a time.
只需要轻轻一击就解决了
One putt, we'II get that par.
现在就是要细心  稳定
Nice and steady now.
让球滚动  就能进洞
Make it roll, it'II seek the hole.
太容易了
Easy peazy, Iemon squeezy.
他不可能打不进的
He's not supposed to miss those.
今天早上的第三个了
Third one this morning.
他到底怎么了
What the devil's wrong with him?
我确实不知道  先生
I'm sure I don't know, sir.
打到树林里去了  你们这帮蠢货
It's in the bleedin' trees, you great bunch o' ninnies.
特德  你运气真差啊  老伙计
Ted! Rotten Iuck, old boy!
-才是第一天  感觉如何  -还有很多高尔夫赛要打
- Just one of those days, what? - Still a Iot of golf to play yet!
势利小人
Toffee-nosed git.
有两类选手
There are only two types of player:
一类是绷着神经要赢比赛
Those who keep their nerves in control and win championships,
一类却相反
and those who do not.
嘿  弗朗西斯  那个大块头是谁
Hey, Francis, who's that big, fat guy?
哦  天哪  是塔夫脱总统
Oh, my gosh. It's President T aft.
瞎扯  是塔夫脱总统吗
Get out! President T aft?
是美国总统塔夫脱吗
The United States President T aft?
-你以前见过总统吗  -第一次
- You ever seen a president before? - First time.
嘿  总统先生  你在那儿做什么
Hey! How you doin' there, Mr. President?
弗朗西斯  刚才的最后一洞你打出小鸟球吗
Francis! Did you just birdie your Iast hole?
我想是的  弗兰克
I guess I did, Frank.
天哪  弗朗西斯  你紧跟在瓦顿之后
Holy smokes, Francis, you're tied with Vardon.
-你是第二名  -我吗
- You're in second place. - I am?
塔夫脱总统在谈论你  是塔夫脱总统啊
President Taft is talking about you. President Taft.
很难相信是吧
Isn't it incredible?
嘿  伙计们  我们有工作
OK, we're working here, buddy.
不要听他们的
Don't Iisten to him.
我们打我们的比赛  让那些人去为他们的事情烦心吧
We play our game, Iet those guys worry about theirs.
我紧跟在
I'm tied...
你跟在Vardan后面  你是第二名
You're tied with Vardon. You're in second place.
哦  天哪
Oh, God.
该死的
Thanks for nothin'.
我们得冷静一下  弗朗西斯
We gotta settle down now, Francis.
哦  是吗  我们该怎么做
Oh, yeah? How are we gonna do that?
你应该打得更好
You're just gonna have to play better.
让自己冷静下来
Keep your head down.
好吧  给我5号铁头球棍
AII right, gimme the mashie.
你不该用这支球棍
You're not gonna reach with that.
如果他可以  我就可以
If he can, I can.
在第二轮  哈利·瓦顿拉开了
In round two, Harry Vardon's pulled even
与防守方冠军约翰·麦克德莫特  的差距
with the defending champion, John McDermott,
但是威尔弗雷德·里德先生  却一杆一杆的追赶上来
but Mr. Wilfred Reid is matching him shot for shot.
经过一个早上的糟糕表现
After a poor showing this morning,
特德·雷看上去  就像个被围困的疯狂野兽
Ted Ray's stalking the grounds Iike a mad brute.
他  疯狂野兽
He... Mad brute.
也许他在这场锦标赛  还有点希望
He may yet have something to say about this championship.
安静
Quiet.
继续  继续  继续
Go, go, go, go!
进去
Get in there.
哎呀
BIimey.
他们太容易激动了
They're easily entertained.
我就指望你了  老伙计
I'm counting on you, old boy,
瓦顿和那粗野的家伙  恐怕没法赢
if Vardon and that great ape of his can't deliver.
事实上  都是为了英格兰
Quite. AII for England.
收起那些对报纸说的  冠冕堂皇的话
Save that patriotic gibberish for the newspapers.
总理答应我说  如果带回这个奖杯
The prime minister has promised me a seat in his cabinet
就让我进入内阁
if I bring back this trophy.
果真如此  我会记得你的  威尔弗雷德
And rest assured, Wilfred, you will be remembered.
啊  打的好啊  哈利
Ah. Bravo, Harry.
你领先我一点
You're tied with me for the Iead.
-你打的很好  先生  -为了国王和国家  如何
- Very well played, sir. - AII for King and country, what?
威尔弗雷德打的很出色  比你带来的那个雷好多了
Wilfred played splendidly, more than can be said for your man Ray.
他就像个野蛮人
Wild as a Hottentot.
虽然他在第一轮里表现不俗  但他不可能在淘汰赛中胜出
After his appalling first round, he won't survive the cut.
他们究竟在做什么
What on earth are they going on about?
特德·雷刚刚打破了得分记录
Ted Ray's just broken the course scoring record.
天啊  雷紧跟在第二
By Jove, Ray's tied for second!
奥密特先生  能问个问题吗
Mr. Ouimet? One question, sir!
弗朗西斯
Francis!
嘿  我以为你回学校了
Hey! I thought you'd gone back to college!
-我还以为你放弃比赛了  -我改变主意了  不是吗
- I thought you quit playing! - I guess I changed my mind, huh?
-真是太好了  -是的
- That's wonderful! - Yeah.
很高兴能见到你  你明天能来吗
It's great to see you. Can you come tomorrow?
-我明天得走了  -明天来吧
- I have to Ieave tomorrow! - Come back tomorrow!
你是他的球童吗
Are you his caddie?
把这个给他  好吗
Give this to him, would you?
幸运符
For Iuck.
这种东西谁需要啊
Dames. Who needs 'em?
今天打得不错啊  奥密特先生
Fine play today, Mr. Ouimet.
谢谢  先生  你也打得很好
Thank you, sir. You too.
我只是运气好而已
It's mostly dumb Iuck, though.
运气只是对我而言的
On my part. Not on your part.
你不需要运气  而我却需要
You don't need Iuck. I need Iuck.
嗯  那祝你好运
Well, good Iuck, then.
谢谢你  先生
Thank you, sir.
我把它们都擦干净了  连手柄也擦了
I cleaned 'em good. Wiped the grips too.
你今天真是做的太棒了
You did just fine out there today.
你也一样  弗朗西斯
You too, Francis.
你明天还能逃出来吗
You gonna be able to skip school again tomorrow?
让他们试试看能不能阻止我
Let 'em try and stop me.
那好  路上小心
AII right, well, you get home safe.
嘿  你不用担心我
Hey, don't you worry about me.
明天一大早
I'II meet you right here.
我会在这里等你的
Early bird gets the worm.
一言为定
Deal.
小姐们  我只能说  当比赛开始时
AII I can say, Iadies, is that when the day began,
我简直没法想象
I scarcely imagined that I'd find myself
我竟然能紧跟在  伟大的哈利·瓦顿之后
tied for the Iead with the immortal Harry Vardon,
并且领先曾经的王者特德·雷两杆
and two strokes ahead of the ever-so-capable Ted Ray.
啊  说曹操  曹操就到
Ah. Speak of the devil, and up he pops.
对不起  小姐们  我要离开一会儿
Excuse me, Iadies. I'II be with you presently.
我简直是太喜欢美国妞了
I simply adore Americans.
活力四射  那么的迷人  那么的天真
The exuberance, such charming naiveté.
你是怎么找到她们的  特德
How do you find them, Ted?
我想你在家一定很在行
I should imagine you feel right at home.
她们有一大堆礼节要遵从  却又渴望有人挤压她们的大胸脯
They clasp all manner of the huddled, yearning masses to their bosoms.
甚至是低级的高尔夫选手
Even the Iowly golf professional.
你知道吗  我可以预言
You know, I can foresee a day,
当他们邀请你们这类人去俱乐部时
given their democratic standards,
肯定是和你们谈民主问题
when they invite your kind into their clubhouses.
哦  他们如何忍受得了
Well, how could they resist?
从泽西岛来的两个可怜家伙  还是白手起家的
Two poor Iads from Jersey, up from nothing.
从工人阶级到平民百姓
Working-class heroes to the great unwashed.
泽西岛曾经只是
When all Jersey's ever given us
提供我们马铃薯和奶牛
are potatoes and dairy cows...
不要看
Don't Iook over there.
对不起  哈利  我没法控制自己
Sorry, Harry. I couldn't contain myself.
他也一样
Neither could he.
他不应该把泽西岛也牵扯进来
He shouldn't have brought Jersey into it.
上帝啊  我的鼻子
My God. My nose.
我看起来还好吧
Do I Iook all right?
说的非常坦诚  里德先生  有了进步
Quite frankly, Mr. Reid, it's an improvement.
那么  你真的见到总统了
So, did you really see the President?
他向我挥手了
He waved at me.
不可能
No.
真的  塔夫脱总统真的是做了
Yes, he did. President Taft.
你能相信弗朗西斯吗
Can you believe Francis?
今晚我睡楼下如何
Why don't I sleep downstairs tonight?
不  你睡楼上
No. You sleep upstairs.
-为了明天的比赛  你需要好的睡眠  -我没事
- You'II need your sleep for tomorrow. - I'm OK.
哦  亚瑟
Oh! Arthur.
他们称呼你奥密特先生
So, they call you Mr. Ouimet.
而对其他人则直呼其名
The others, it just says their names.
爸爸  他们是职业选手
Well, Father, they're professionals.
我只是个业余的
I'm an amateur.
吃点甜点吧
Let's have some dessert.
不用  等等  坐下来
No, wait, wait. Sit, sit.
现在他们都在谈论你
They're all talking about you now.
说就算你赢了  也得不到奖金
It say here that if you win, you get no money.
其他人有奖金  你却什么也没有
The others make money, you get nothing.
这说明了什么
What does that prove?
他们甚至都不给你工资  这是个什么工作
They don't even pay you! What kind of work is that?
-亚瑟  -干吗
- Arthur. - What?
我给你拿盘子来
I'II fix you a plate.
快点  用力拉
Come on, you! Pull!
早上好  哈利
Morning, Harry.
讨厌的英国式天气
Dreadful English weather.
-睡得怎么样  -就像个婴儿
- How'd you sleep? - Like a baby.
过两个小时就要醒来并且哭闹
Woke up every two hours and cried.
嘿  弗朗西斯
Hey, Francis!
我昨晚梦见你打出了72杆的好成绩
I had a dream Iast night that you shot a 72!
真的  在风暴中要打出来可不容易
Yeah? It won't be easy in a nor'easter.
你可是在这种天气中打出过的
You've played this course in weather Iike this.
你说的对  这是个打出72杆的好日子
You're right. It's a good day for a 72.
好耶
Okeydokey, pipe and smokey.
如果英国人赢了我们  他们会说我以前只是侥幸赢的
If the Brits beat us, they'II say it was a fluke I ever won it.
他们会说这是他们的比赛  我们还不够格
They'II say it's their game, and we're not good enough.
这是我们的公开赛
This is our Open.
是的  真不可思议
Yes. Marvelous.
奥密特  奥密特  奥-密-特
Ouimet. Ouimet. O-U-I-M-E-T.
三轮过后他只是比瓦顿和雷落后一杆
He's only one stroke behind Vardon and Ray after three rounds.
移走它  用背去顶
Move it! Put your backs into it now!
再挖深些  我们走
Go a Iittle deeper there! There we go.
不在这  去那边看看
Not here. Over there.
好好检查一下尽头
Watch that end go through!
-往下放  -好的  先生
- And move on down! - Yes, sir!
谢谢
Thank you.
雷只需轻轻一击就处于领先了
Ray needs that putt for the Iead.
我不想听别人是怎么做的
I don't want to hear how anyone else is doing.
我们打我们的球
We play our own game.
我们现在处在什么位置
Where do we stand?
你得用标准杆数通过最后5个洞  才能追上特德  处于领先
You'd still have to par the Iast five holes to tie Ted for the Iead.
形势很糟糕  哈利
Dreadful conditions, Harry.
没有人会指责你  如果你
No one would blame you if you came...
谢谢  伯纳德
Thank you, Bernard.
球进水里了  他完了
He's done for in there.
他不可能追上了
No chance he catches him now.
你怎么啦  伙计
What's got into you, old thing?
别过来惹我烦
You had to go and get me angry.
哦  是我的错
Oh, yes. My mistake.
打完这个
When I par this one,
我们就得尽全力去打明天的
we'II have to go at it again tomorrow.
决赛吗  真讨厌
A playoff? What a bother.
是的  但是必须
Yes, but there it is.
以前从没有看见过  你比赛的时候抽烟
Never seen you smoke on the job before.
只是提前了4个洞的时间而已
Should've started four holes earlier.
没有什么好担心的了
Ah, all square again.
这个年轻人没有机会赶超了
Not a chance this stripling bears up.
也许不是这样的
Probably not.
让他们看
Let 'em Iook.
我们这些紧跟着的  就只有你还在打了
We're tied, and you're the one still playing.
最好能避开这种英国式的恶劣天气
Might as well get out of this beastly New England weather
举杯庆祝英国的胜利吧
and raise a glass to British victory.
谁在给他扛包  是个侏儒吗
What's that carrying his bag, a Pygmy?
我们需要两杆  一杆这儿  另一杆在16洞
We need two strokes. One here, one at the 1 6th...
弗朗西斯  别想那么多  你不可能一下子把他们拿下来
Francis, don't think so much. You can't play 'em all at once.
一个一个地打
You gotta take 'em one at a time.
每次一杆  要两杆  要两杆  六个洞
One at a time, two down. Two down, six to play.
我可以在这里得一杆  在16洞得一杆
I can get one here and another on 1 6.
那个女孩让我把这个交给你
That girl wanted me to give you this.
-哪个女孩  -莎拉
- What girl? - Sarah.
莎拉给你的
Sarah gave you this?
你就戴上吧  别让它淋湿了
Just put it on. Don't get all sloppy over it.
为了英国
To England.
那究竟是怎么回事
What the hell was that?
一切还没有结束
It's not over yet.
哦  哦  瞧  谁回来了
Well, well. Look who's back.
-很好  -打得不错
- Nice. - Nice shot!
让我们过去  这是奥密特的母亲
Let us through. It's Ouimet's mother.
情况怎么样啦
What's happenin'?
他在16洞这里思考
He hit it stone dead at 1 6.
他只有一杆的机会
He's only down one.
什么意思  这是好事情吗
What does that mean? Is it good?
如果他做到了  就会进决赛
If he makes this, it's a playoff.
天哪  这几乎超越了人的计算能力
Dear me, it's almost beyond one's ability to calculate.
啊  请别介意  我喝口酒
Ah, don't mind if I do.
他不可能成功的  不可能
He can't keep this up. It's impossible.
该死的
I'II be damned.
哦  弗朗西斯
Oh, Francis!
明天瓦顿  雷和奥密特先生
There will be an 1 8-hole playoff tomorrow
将进行18洞的比赛
between Vardon, Ray and Mr. Ouimet
决出冠军
to decide the Championship.
这个男孩是上帝给的礼物
That boy's a gift from the gods.
国内正在夜以继日的印刷
They're printing 'round the clock at home.
天哪  猜猜他们能在这儿卖什么
Cripes! Imagine what they're selling here.
如果有机会  我是不是该买块烂抹布
Should have bought one of these rags when I had the chance.
他敢于站出来  但是他会受到重创的
It's a bold charge, but he's spent his powder.
伙计们  这是两个人的比赛
It's a two-man game now, my Iads.
英国人的决赛
An all-English final.
嗯  我们得看看
Well, we'II see.
嘿  哈利  真难以想象
Come on, Harry. It's inconceivable.
那个人居然是个该死的业余选手
The man's a bloody amateur.
你上一次被击败  是什么时候
When was the Iast time you were beaten...
在男人和男人的对决中
Have you ever been beaten, man-to-man,
在你的职业生涯中  你有被业余选手打败过吗
in your entire career by an amateur?
业余选手是不可能赢得公开赛的
Amateurs do not win Opens.
该死的  最近一个赢得比赛的
Hell, the Iast one who won it back home
也是40年前了  而且他是个绅士
was 40 years ago, and he was a gentleman.
而这个人  他什么也不是  他只是个农民  一个土老冒
This one's nothing of the kind. He's a peasant. Common clay.
他会被打得惨败的
He'II fold Iike an accordion.
我需要休息一下
I need my rest.
如果他不能把球击出一英里  他将只是个挖沟的
If he couldn't hit the ball a country mile, he'd be digging ditches.
你去哪儿  哈利  坐下来吧
Where are you going, Harry? Sit down with me.
和我一起吃  放松一下自己
Eat with me. Enjoy yourself.
我来这是为了赢比赛
I came here to win a trophy.
也就是说  我和特德·雷能自己应对
On the face of it, Ted Ray or I should carry it off.
不是为了你  也不是为了英国
Not for you, not for England,
只是为了成为最好的那份荣誉  这就是我们打比赛的原因
but for bloody pride at being the best. That's why we do this.
如果明天奥密特先生赢得比赛的话  那是因为他是最棒的
And if Mr. Ouimet wins tomorrow, it's because he's the best,
是因为他本人
because of who he is.
不管他父亲是谁  也不管他有没有钱
Not who his father was, not how much money he's got,
只是因为他本人
because of who he bloody is!
我希望你记住
And I'II thank you to remember that.
我还要感谢你  做为一位绅士所应当表现出来的尊敬
And I'II thank you to show the respect a gentleman gives as a matter of course.
晚安
Good night.
你想他输掉  是吗
Do you want him to fail?
这样你才会安心  是吗
Is that the only satisfaction you can take from what he's doin'?
难道你认为我会让他伤心
You think I want him to break his heart?
玛丽  如果他输了  你会怎么做
What will you do, Mary, when he fails?
到时候  你如何帮他
How will you help him then?
你所能做的只是鼓励他
AII you ever do is encourage him.
是的  我就是鼓励他
That's right. I do encourage him.
他有天赋
He has a God-given talent,
这是他的一个机会  能展现他的才能
and this is his one chance to give a voice to it.
他只是想让你感到自豪
He's just tryin' to make you proud.
真难以置信  这个没有经过训练的男孩
"It seems impossible to believe that this untested boy
居然有希望  打败两位经验丰富的冠军选手
could hope to beat two seasoned champions."
一个凡人对付两个巨人
One David against two Goliaths.
明天  在让人难以置信的场合
He'll have to face Vardon and Ray alone,
他将独自面对瓦顿和雷
with a night to sleep on the incredible situation
他会发现一个非常不一样的自我
in which he so shockingly finds himself.
虽然
Although, I suspect,
我对他今天所表现出来的异常冷静  表示怀疑
from the unearthly calm he showed today,
但是他会睡得比平时都好
he will sleep better than most.
我不是很确定奥密特能赢
I am not certain I believe Ouimet can win,
我放弃去预测的想法
but I have given up all attempts at prophecy.
明天的比赛  我将公平对待
I will start tomorrow's round with an open mind.
这将是最伟大的比赛
It should be the greatest game ever played.
美国公开赛  第三天  决赛
年轻人  我们得商量一下
Young man. We've been talking this over.
商量什么
T alking what over?
委员们认为  今天你会需要很多的帮助
The members feel you need as much help as you can get out there today.
-什么帮助  -依据规则
- What kind of help? - According to the rules,
只有你的球童能给你出主意
your caddie is the only person who can give you advice.
今天你需要一个  真正懂得我们的规则的人
You need someone with you today who really knows our course.
-是的  -埃迪做得很好
- Exactly. - Eddie's doin' a great job for me.
天哪  奥密特
For God's sake, Ouimet!
这可是美国公开赛
This is the U.S. Open,
不是低级的俱乐部赛
not some junior club championship.
在和我谈之前  你跟埃迪说了这件事情吗
You told Eddie this before talking to me?
你不用向那种孩子解释
Oh, you can't reason with a boy Iike that.
我们会让他退出  并给他一笔钱
We'II take up a collection for him and pay him handsomely.
他的家人应该会需要
I understand his family could use it.
不要让他们这么做  弗朗西斯
Don't Iet 'em do it, Francis!
你确定吗  你知道的  我可没有钱给你  埃迪
Is it true? You know I can't pay you, Eddie.
我不会为了10元钱来做的  我也不会为了100元来做
I wouldn't do it for ten bucks. I wouldn't do it for a hundred!
嘿  听着  你认为我会替换掉你  是吗
Hey, Iisten. You think I'd replace you?
但是他们说你想这么做
But they said you'd want to.
谁会去管他们的想法呢  谁会去关心呢
Who cares what they said? Who cares?
只有你和我  我们是个团队  不是吗
This is me and you. We're a team. OK?
他们没有权利
They don't get a vote in this.
好了吗
AII right?
你在外面等我
I'II meet you outside.
不要再和我的球童讨论这件事
Don't ever talk to my caddie again.
奥密特先生先打
Mr. Ouimet will play first.
达尔文先生是记分员  负责记录你们的得分
Mr. Darwin will act as honorary marker and keep your scores.
先生们  时间到了
Gentlemen, it's time.
-他出来了  -祝你好运  孩子
- Here he comes! - Good Iuck, son!
-加油  年轻人  -加油  奥密特
- Come on, young man! - Come on, Ouimet!
加油  弗朗西斯  加油
Come on, Francis! Come on!
给我们一个惊喜  孩子
Give us a strong show, son.
-在那你得了5分是吗  -是的
- Five for you there? - That's right.
你能赢  弗朗西斯
You can do it, Francis.
-什么  -嗯  对不起
- What? - Wha... Sorry.
我刚才有说话吗
Did I say something?
厉害
That was big.
他们也是凡人
They're human.
什么
What's that?
我能打败他们  埃迪
I can play these guys, Eddie.
是啊  谁说你不能了
Yeah? Who said you couldn't?
也许他们根本就不是人
Maybe they're not human.
这是他上次输了的地方
This is where he fell apart the Iast time.
那是昨天的事情了
That was yesterday.
莎拉
Sarah!
你在这干什么  你应该待在学校
What are you doing here? You're supposed to be in school.
别无聊了  爸爸
Don't be ridiculous, Father.
他不是很优秀  哈利
He's not cracking, Harry.
我也是这么想的
The thought occurred to me.
英国人自己的比赛
"An all-English final."
请安静
Quiet, please.
该死的
Stymied.
-你做什么  -瞧我的
- What are you doin'? - I'II show you.
快点  结束他
Come on, now. Finish him.
让我们看看他会不会崩溃
Let's see if he cracks now.
前面右边的注意
Fore right!
他会被这些树阻挡完蛋的
He's dead in those trees.
中号铁棍
Mid iron.
在树林中结束了
Done in by the monarch of the forest.
该你了  老家伙  我结束了
Down to you, old thing. I'm done.
有些遗憾  不过这是重大的比赛
Pity. It's a great match.
就是这种精神  哈利
That's the spirit, Harry.
加油  奥密特
Come on, Ouimet.
你准备打去哪
Where you going with that?
-穿过拐角  -那儿有个沙坑
- Gonna cut the corner. - There's a bunker down there.
如果他打过去  就只需要推杆了
If he's over it, he's a chip away.
我们不知道他是不是打过去了  这是个圈套
We don't know he's over it. It's a trick.
这是我们的机会  弗朗西斯
This is our chance, Francis.
象昨天一样打到那儿
Run it in there, just Iike yesterday.
天哪  弗朗西斯领先了一杆
My God. Francis has a one-stroke Iead with one to play.
请待在线外
Hold the Iine, please.
请待在线外  请待在线外
Hold the Iine! Hold the Iine!
放轻松
Take your time.
给我毛巾  埃迪
Let me have that towel, Eddie.
做得不错
Well done.
你需要这一击完成72杆目标  你能做到的
You need this for 72. You can do it.
让球旋转  让它进洞
Read it, roll it and hole it.
谢谢
Thank you! Thank you!
-你做到了  -谢谢
- You did it! - Thank you!
瞧  埃迪  我们赢了  我们赢了
Look, Eddie, we did it! We did it!
不  我不能要
No! No! I can't take it!
把帽子给埃迪
Pass the hat for Eddie!
Pass the hat for Eddie! Here!
把帽子给埃迪  把帽子给
Pass the hat for Eddie! Pass the hat for...
打得很好  奥密特先生  是场了不起的比赛
Well played, Mr. Ouimet. That was a great game.
我很尽兴
I enjoyed it.
我也是
So did I.
当然  你赢了
Yes, you did.
祝贺你的成功  这是你应得的
Congratulations on your success. You deserve it.
谢谢
Thank you.
以后我们会再比赛的
We'II play again sometime.
瞧这东西
Look at this thing.
-好大啊  -有什么意义吗
- It's a whopper. - Isn't that something?
他们让你拿回家吗
They Iet you take it home with ya?
没有人阻拦我
Nobody's tried to stop me.
嗯  他们还得通过我这一关
Well, they'd have to get past me.
埃迪  你知道吗
You know somethin', Eddie?
你和我会成为好朋友的
You and I are gonna be great friends.
是的  弗朗西斯
You said it, Francis.
第二年  哈利·瓦顿第六次  赢得了英国公开赛冠军
至今没有人能打破这个记录
他于1937年去世  被公认是英国最伟大的高尔夫球手
弗朗西斯·奥密特成为了  一位著名的商人
他赢得了两届美国业余锦标赛冠军
并成为该项赛事的终身荣誉大使
埃迪·洛维利成为了一个亿万富翁
弗朗西斯和埃迪终身保持着朋友关系